[Music]
um
foreign
[Music]
so
[Applause]
[Music]
oh
cool
[Music]
me
and
[Music]
what
i
[Music]
i'm losing my weight
through this darkness
she was heartless
[Music]
through this darkness
she was heartless
in every way i'm losing my way
[Music]
i'm losing my weight
through this darkness
she was heartless
in every way i'm losing my way
[Music]
so
[Applause]
[Music]
she was
through this darkness
[Music]
i'm losing my way
hello
[Music]
i know it's all right here but follow
your heart dude
[Music]
i know your dreams are clear don't you
know we all
feel
[Music]
don't be afraid
you should take the first step
and the rest will
[Music]
[Applause]
but time should make you be your last
[Music]
forget
you should take the first step
and the rest will
[Music]
oh
[Laughter]
uh
[Music]
[Applause]
now
[Music]
so
don't listen to what they say
you can't take it slow
and when the night rider comes around
[Music]
mr days with the break of the drums
easily so
[Music]
of the line
this is where we go
[Music]
top down with the cruise control lights
out with the radio on
it's crazy
[Music]
so easily so
easily
[Music]
so easily
everybody knows inside that this won't
stop
the rain coming down tonight we just
watch
[Music]
i know it's too late i had so much i
wanna say
i'll just have to wait
[Music]
as the lights go off
the sky is the last time you'll reach
[Music]
chaos
raindrops
filling up your eyes is the worst
[Music]
so
to
everybody knows inside that we've had it
good
good things like we thought they
would
[Music]
it's only the end
me or you
[Music]
chaos
raindrops
filling up your eyes
[Music]
oh
crazy
[Music]
and as i wake up from this crazy dream
i hope the things remain as they seem
cause as i wake up from this crazy dream
oh this dream
[Music]
i had a dream about you last night and
we were listening to far side
something the sun started spinning in
the past eyes so i kept singing to the
bar side we were on the last ride
i say it is the past but the present
moving fast i ain't thinking about the
last time
it's fine but they were saying that you
asked my brothers if i'm ready for the
last line remember in the
way you move it's bugging me out
[Music]
and as i wake up from this crazy dream
i hope the things remain as they seem
cause as i wake up from this crazy tree
hold this dream
[Music]
is
and as i wake up from this crazy dream
i hope the things remain as they sing
cause i saw wake up from this crazy tree
hold this dream
and as i wake up from this crazy dream
i hope the things remain as they sing
cause as i wake up from this crazy tree
hold this dream
[Music]
crazy
baby remember when we turned onto
a rainy day
baby remember when we turned onto a
rainy day
[Music]
baby remember when we turned on
and as the sun goes down and the stars
come out of play
[Music]
i bet tomorrow i'll be sleeping
sleeping all day
and this fire offline why is it
burning so slowly
i can't stop thinking of you like the
five pounds you owe
me cause you're on my mind
[Music]
you're on my mind
please tell me that you feel the same
that we're
on the same train
if you're a little bit late and miss it
that would be a great shame
i miss your sweet sweet kisses and
loving
when they were mine
when are you down i'll make sure
i'm in town
cause you're
[Music]
i
please give me the time
[Music]
so
cause you're on my mind my mind
you're on my mind
[Music]
my mind
so
[Music]
do
[Applause]
[Music]
i wish you'd known
how far i'd go
i was stuck in my mind stuck in my mind
i was stuck in my mind
i wish you'd seen
who i could have been
[Music]
i was stuck in my mind
in my mind i was stuck in my mind
[Music]
when you go you go you go
i'm a sun in the sky
this guy
[Music]
i miss the way
we love that day
when you were mine when you were
still stuck in my mind
[Music]
i miss the thrill
stays with me still
all of the time all of the time
still stuck in my mind
[Music]
when you go you go
i'm a sunless sky
[Music]
oh
wow
[Music]
bye
boom
[Music]
oh
hey
[Music]
thank you
one two three four
[Music]
i love the way it flows i love the way
it grows
there's something in this sound that
takes me far
it's like a special song i can move my
mood along
but i cannot say you'll hit through my
guitar
she told me at the baseline and
everything will be alright
she told me that the groove is mine it
will take us through the night
and we're all gone
i can't explain i'll never know
but it's beautiful you can't take this
away from me
the way i hear the melody the ways bring
clarity running through me
you can't take this away from me oh the
way
[Music]
i love the way it sings all the joy that
it brings
remember skating down the road towards
the park
i can never say no you with the summer
glow
the music gives me sun when winter
starts
she told me at the baseline everything
will be alright
she told me that the beat is mine it
will rock us through the night
[Music]
and where i go
i can't explain i'll never know
but it's beautiful you can't take this
away from me
oh the way i hear the melody the waves
bring clarity
running through me you can't take this
away from me
oh the way i hear the melody the waves
bring clarity
running through me hey
[Music]
clarity run through me yeah it's running
through me
yo i wear notes like coats blues like
dudes
warm from the rhythm soul that glows
that bounce to my bones
jazz in my spot the hop is my home rap
is my grind
i'm grinding on the backside of life we
dance she threw me a chance
her hands in my pants actually my
pocket's holding me tight
whispering a dream i got hold of the
night blood type a rhythm that's
throbbing my vein
wake up and write it on the path of
pains like church the organ will invite
the tears like burp the crying let you
know i'm here
held by the song that gave me a name
dressed by the verse that gave me a
claim
just basing the lines safe to inhale and
if you live well
belong
[Music]
through harmony someone harming me that
won't be done
i stand protected by the laws of fun i
am perfected through the rhymes and run
walking this way and leave the party
stun this music
didn't launch me no aim i've landed
on some plane where i am i can't explain
or never know but it's beautiful
so you can't take this away from me oh
the way i hear the melody
the waves bring clarity running through
me
come on y'all you can't take this away
from me
oh the way i hear the melody the waves
bring
run it through me
[Music]
and as the sun goes down
and the stars come out of play
[Music]
i bet tomorrow i'll be sleeping
sleeping all day
[Laughter]
and this fire i feel
why is it burning so slowly
[Music]
i can't stop thinking of you
like the five pounds you owe me
cause you're on my mind
[Music]
please tell me that you feel the same
that we're on the same train
if you're a little bit late and miss it
that would be a great shame
[Music]
i miss your sweet sweet kisses
loving when they were mine
when are you down i'll make sure i'm
in time
[Music]
cause you're on my mind
you're on my mind
you're all i can find
cause you're on my mind
[Music]
oh the colors they shine through
night and i'm thinking of you
he's dawn of every day
you're on my mind
[Music]
so
you're on my mind
[Music]
you're all i can find
cause you're my
my mind
[Music]
you're my mind
you're my man
you're
my cheek brushes against his smooth on
stubble for a moment
and then it's gone he walks along the
platforms if in a dream
every fiber in me wants to shout and
scream stop
to run across to him and take him in my
arms to tell him i
love you you silly silly man i love you
[Music]
but instead i stand still heart
cracking those little curls on the back
of his head
bouncing as he steps out of my life
[Music]
i'm
i hope that the fire we
both made still burns a little in you
i wrote
[Music]
our memories on my screen
love is in this mystic dream baby come
back to me
come back to me too much time on my
phone
baby do you still sleep alone
come back to me
come back to me remember
a fresh
[Music]
what you meant to me what was it mystery
movie
[Music]
i heard that you move
somewhere far away is your number
the same as before
i can't ignore the time
may have changed your
[Music]
such a sentimental way to groove
i hope it still touches you baby come
back to me
come back to me it kills me to see you'd
leave
so i came home and made this beat baby
come back to me
come back to me remember moving
[Music]
remember
[Applause]
[Music]
what you realized what you meant to me
what was it
[Music]
remember me let's set the scene
you and me what could have been still
swimming
in all lovers dreams still playing on
new movie screens remember me
let's set the scene
[Music]
remember me let's set the scene
you and me what could have been
[Music]
you and me what could have been still
swimming in
all of his dreams
[Music]
something you gave me
i focus on
a hundred moments ready sewn
[Laughter]
into my memory
[Music]
but you still come loose though
the time it grows
i know you'd like to take it slow
but i've got to know
[Music]
that's why you got to come here
uh
[Music]
easy to find me
you to the moments that you've never
known
[Music]
keep for the future
maybe we will stay here
maybe somewhere close
but i'm never sure where you will go
so i've got to know
that's why you got to come here
[Music]
oh
bye
[Music]
so
foreign
bye
[Music]
you
uh
[Music]
bye
foreign
[Music]
done
so tonight i'm sleeping under
[Music]
when i closed my eyes you're still
climbing up with
me tonight i'm sleeping under the stars
cause i feel it and you're climbing
[Music]
your absence used to rip me apart
when i close my eyes
[Music]
me
so
[Music]
you