what's going on guys john elder here
from coding.com and in this video
we're going to work on the addition
function for a calculator with kivy and
python
all right guys like i said in this video
we're going to work on the addition
function for our calculator
but before we get started if you like
this video you want to see more like it
be sure to smash the like button below
subscribe to the channel give me a
thumbs up for the youtube algorithm
and check out cody.com where i have
dozens of courses with hundreds of
videos that teach you to code
use coupon code youtube want to get 30
membership that's all my courses videos
and books
for one time fee at just 49 which is
insanely cheap
all right it is monday morning here in
vegas the day after the long
thanksgiving holiday hope you guys had a
great holiday weekend if you celebrated
thanksgiving if not
hope you had a great holiday in this
video like i said we're going to work on
the addition function so we've got 99
plus one we hit equal to
boom it hits 100 so we can go 9 plus 3
12 plus 56
68 whatever so that's what we're going
to work on in this video so i've got our
calc.pi file and calc.kv file
from the last video if you didn't see
that video check the link in the comment
section below for the playlist
and the first thing i'm going to do is
head over here and anytime we press a
button
for instance well a number button at
least we want to pass that number
into a function on our in our python
file and then do something with it
right so let's start out with this one
and i'm just going to go
on underscore press like we've done
before let's go
root dot and let's call this button
underscore press
because it's very original very original
name and let's just pass in
seven right so this is the seven key the
seven
button we're just going to pass in the
number seven into this function now we
haven't created this function yet we'll
do that in just a second so
i can just copy this and we can come
through here and let's just
for each of these i know this is very
exciting but we'll just sort of paste
this
in so we've got nine there's probably a
faster way to do this but it's monday
morning so we're just gonna kind of
manually plow through this here so this
is gonna be
five and this will be
six put a little space after each one
just for fun
one almost done
and this one will be two and there we go
this one will be it will be three
and then we've got some more and let's
also do zero for now
and we'll leave the rest of these for
later but
okay we've got all these numbers now
we've got this button press function we
need to actually create it so let's head
back over to our calc.pi
file and inside of our my layout widget
let's
comment this and create a button
pressing
function right whatever
so let's define press button and we want
to pass in self and let's pass in a
variable called button
right so whenever we come over here and
click on one of these for instance zero
we're p we're passing in zero and that
zero will be assigned to this button
variable
and then inside of this function we can
do whatever we want with it okay so what
do we want to do with it well
remember our calculator when it starts
there's a zero sitting in the text box
at the top
well if there's a zero we we probably
want to get rid of that zero
right it's just sort of there for visual
purposes it doesn't really do anything
at this point so we need to
run a little if statement to say hey is
there a zero there so
i'm going to create a variable
that contains whatever
was in the text box already
all right okay that is a long comment so
i'm just i'm going to call this prior
whatever was priorly priorly whatever
was previously in there
we'll assign it to this variable and so
we get that by calling self
dot ids dot calc underscore
input dot text and you remember from the
last video if we
head up to the top first thing here our
text input we give it an id of calc
input
so we're calling whatever the i whatever
has the id of calc input
what is the text that's in there well
whatever it is assign it to prior
so now let's run an if statement
and let's uh determine
if zero is sitting there
right so let's go if prior
equals zero what do we want to do well
if it's zero we probably want to get rid
of it
we don't want the zero there most likely
so
we can go we could just call this thing
right here
so let me just copy this so we can set
that equal to nothing
and what else do we want to do well
let's say we press the 9 button
we want 9 to show up in the text box so
we need to add that there
so let's do this i'm going to add this
as an f string and let's just pass in
button
so remember this button gets assigned
whatever the number of the button is
that we click so if we click the nine
button
we'll get rid of the zero and we'll add
and we'll put nine in there
right so let's go ahead and save this
and run it just to see if that worked
let's go python calc dot pi
so we can say 7 boom 7 appears now it
doesn't do anything else because 0
is not sitting there right so if we go
back to 0 and click 3
it does something so ok that works now
we
need an else statement so we've got if
if it equals 0
do this else
what do we want to do well we want to
put
say we click the 9 and the 9 is sitting
there
but we want to say 97 so we want to
click the 7 button so we
the 9 is already sitting there so we
need to account for that and we need to
put the 7 behind it so it'll say 97
right so we can do that just by going
self well we can just copy this whole
thing
and paste that in there let's give us
some space here
and inside of here we want another f
string and we want to put whatever was
in there prior
first so we could go prior and then we
also want to put whatever the button is
so if nine was there already
so prior will become nine
this is false so this won't get run but
this will and it will put nine here
as prior plus then whatever we click the
second time
seven for instance or whatever so okay
let's save this and run it see if that
worked
so we can say 97
or 973 or 9730.
we could just keep clicking things and
they keep appearing
on there so okay that works good now if
we keep going you'll notice
boom it disappears we'll need to fix
that but we'll do that much later
we'll just leave that for now now let's
work on the plus sign
so when we've got 9 here say we want to
add 3 we would click this plus sign
when we do that i want the plus sign to
appear right there
right so then we can also hit 3 again
and then 3 will appear
so that's what we'll do when we click
the plus sign so let's do that now
so let's head over to our calc thing and
let's let's look for our plus sign and
i'm just going to do a quick search here
so here's our plus button get rid of
that
now let's create an on underscore press
for this guy
and let's go root dot let's call this
add
let's create an add function right so
okay
we can save this head back over here
and let's come in here and
let's create addition
function so let's define add
and we also want to pass in self now
when we did this button press one we
also passed in the button
we don't need to do that here because
we're not passing in anything when we
press the plus we just want to
press plus right so okay that's pretty
easy
so again we want to do the same thing
here grab whatever was
previously in the text field so let's
just paste that in
and assign it to this prior variable
right
now all we want to do is take whatever
was previously in there and slap a plus
sign to the end of it
right so we could do that just by
calling
this so
let's say slap a plus sign
[Music]
to the text box whatever
so we could just call that self.ids.calc
dot
calc underscore input.txt and we just
set that equal to
let's do another f string here because
it's just
easier that way and what do we want to
do well we want to take whatever
well we want to take whatever was
previously in there or
prior as we're calling it and then we
just want to slap a plus sign
on after it so we go ahead and save this
let's run this guy
we can go eight plus boom the plus sign
appears now we can say two
we can keep going plus three plus six
whatever
and we're good to go so now we just need
to work on this equal to
and likewise we could do the same thing
for the minus multiplication and
subtraction if we wanted to
we could knock that out real quick just
right here
so let's go let's just look through here
for each of these
here's the minus one we can go on
underscore press
and let's call root.subtract
let me just copy this and we can keep
looking through here here's the
multiplication so we can call
root dot multiply
and let's change this to a lowercase x
that's kind of bugging me it looks weird
and we can come up here and here's the
multiplication we'll call root dot
or here's the division we'll call root
dot divide all right so let's go ahead
and save these
now just very quickly you can just sort
of copy
each of these
we want one two
three add three more so
let's see
this one was subtract
and then down here we just wanna slap a
subtract sign
instead of a plus sign right this one
will be
multiply and again down here
we want the let's put a little star here
that's the
shift in the 8 key on your keyboard and
then
finally this one will be divide
and at the bottom of this guy we'll put
what that division sign so okay now
let's see let's go ahead and save this
and run it real quick just to make sure
that worked we did that kind of fast
so let's go nine times three that seems
to work let's go
nine divided by three that seems to work
let's go nine
minus oh subtract let's see
i misspelled subtract right there okay
so
there you go that seems
good let's run this again just to make
sure so
nine minus three okay
and then nine plus three oops nine plus
three
all right so now we want to work on
this equal to sign and we're just going
to work on the addition one for now
i will do the rest of these in the next
video but this is getting a little bit
long so
okay let's head back over here and let's
look through here
and i'm gonna just do a quick search for
our equal to
there it is and let's go on underscore
press
let's give this a root dot equals
function go ahead and save this
now let's come back up here
and uh create equal
equals to function and let's define
equals we want to pass in self we don't
need to pass in anything else
and just like all of these things we
need to know what was previously in
our text box at the top right
now this is going to get it interesting
because this could be a long thing this
could be
9 plus 2 plus 6 plus nine plus
four plus 106 or it could be four plus
four it could be two things
but it's it's going to be a string of
text
with a plus sign separating different
things
right so we need to sort of break this
apart for
whatever sign is in there and like i
said right now we're going to do
addition so let's do
addition here and now we can we can
determine if
addition if the addition sign is in this
variable right and we can do that just
by calling if and we could go
the plus sign in prior
right so if there's a plus sign in there
what do we want to do
well we need to split apart this string
by the plus sign and so we can do that
we can call let's create a a list a
python list called
number list right and this is going to
equal
prior dot split we want to split it
apart
what do we want to split it by we want
to split it by the plus sign
right so this will now give us a
python list of all of the numbers
split apart by the plus sign so let's
just print this out real quick
num underscore list just to see what
this looks like so let's save this and
run it
so we've got let's say 9 plus 3 plus
2. we hit equal nothing happens but when
we close this we should see a python
list with 9
3 and 2 in it and we do we see a python
list right here with 9 3 and 2 in it now
check this out though these are
quotation marks
which means these aren't numbers these
are strings so we're going to have to
convert them into numbers into integers
and if we want to do math
which we do so let's go ahead and
do that now so we don't need this
let's create a variable called answer
and let's set this equal to zero
or i guess we could set it equal to zero
like that
so now let's create a loop so let's loop
through our list so let's go four
let's say let's call this number for a
number in our
num underscore list we want the answer
to equal answer
plus our number but remember
this number is a string so we need to
convert this to an integer
let's go ahead and do that and then when
this is all done let's just
um let's just print out answer just to
see if this is working so
all right let's go ahead and save this
we need we may need to fiddle with this
a bit
so let's bring this over let's say nine
plus one
equals nothing happens when we close
this
boom it shows us 10 down here so all
right
that seems to work now all we have to do
is instead of printing this to the
terminal
we just want to print this to this thing
right so let me just copy this and let's
just come down here and say
uh print the answer in the text box
so we can set that equal to and let's
just go
answer
now this may not work because this is
now an integer
so we're placing an integer in a text
box so let's go ahead and run it and see
if that will work or not so let's go
nine plus
one nope we get an error
so we need to convert this into a string
as i
suspected so we could just go string
wrap that in a string function all right
now that should work
let's go nine plus one boom ten
and that's it so we can you know 55
plus 5 plus 10 what's that gonna be 70
boom 70 and just that easy and we can
keep going 70 plus
uh 10 gonna be 80 right
plus six very cool and just that easy so
again just
to look through here when we press the
equal to button we want to
put whatever is previously in the text
box in this variable
then we want to split it apart so if
it's 9 plus 3
we want to split the 9 and the 3 apart
by
the plus sign so we want to pull out the
plus sign and put everything else
into a python list so
then we want to loop through this list
and add the things together
right when we do we assign them to this
answer variable that we set to zero up
here
and then finally we just slap it back
into the input box
but remember to convert it to a string
first because i guess input boxes like
strings
and that's all there is to it so we went
through a bunch of stuff in this video
but it was all pretty simple stuff you
know we clicked the buttons
so we're now assigning whatever was in
the whatever the button is
to the text box so if we press nine the
nine appears
now we when we press plus the plus
appears and then when we press equal
it adds them all up it figures out that
this is a addition
and uh it does stuff now for the rest of
these we'll do the same thing we'll do
another if statement
if instead of plus you know we'll do
minus right
whatever now the inside stuff this stuff
in here will be different for each one
minus
multiplication and division and we'll
see why probably in the next video
but uh pretty easy and we're coming
right along so that's all for this video
if you like to be sure to smash the like
button below subscribe to the channel
give me a thumbs up for the youtube
algorithm
and check out codeme.com where you can
use coupon code youtube1 to get 30
memberships your pages 49 taxes all my
courses over 47 courses
hundreds of videos and the pds of all my
best selling coding books doing over a
hundred thousand students learning to
code just like you
my name is john elder from coding.com
and i'll see in the next video