hey guns and welcome back to another
Kibby tutorial so in today's video I'm
gonna be showing you how to create
pop-up windows which is actually very
useful and it's super simple to do this
as well so I'm just gonna start and kind
of build a very basic interface
I like GUI and then we're gonna get to
actually using those pop-ups putting
them on the screen some of the different
options how you can add different
widgets to it and all that so
essentially I have all these things
imported we've talked about them before
a widget object property label import
float layout so I also need to just
import pop-up so I'm going to do is
Kavita uix top pop up and we'll import
pop up like that now what I'll actually
start by doing it just show you guys
right away how to make the pop and then
I'll work into how we can actually
display it onto the screen and like
trigger that event and whatnot so I'm
gonna create a function I'm just gonna
call this show underscore pop-up like
this okay it doesn't need any parameters
and all we're gonna do in here is we're
gonna create a pop-up window and show it
and that way whenever we want to create
a pop-up all we have to do is just
simply call this function and it'll do
that for us so you could put this as a
method Sapor inside your widget class or
inside your my app I'm just gonna leave
it as a function obviously feel free to
do whatever you want so to create a
pop-up what we need to do is need to
have some content for that pop-up so
actually that leads me do we need to
create another class so I'm gonna create
a class I'm just gonna call this P
standing for pop-up and all I'm gonna do
is pass in here and I'm just gonna come
to my my dog f K V final sorry that's
already empty and what I'm gonna do in
here is I'm just going to define a few
widgets that I want to go inside of my
what do you call it my pop-up or whatnot
so what I'm actually gonna do sir is go
back here I'm getting sidetracked and
I'm just gonna make this inherit from
float layout because what I want my
pop-up window to be is a float layout
that contains a few different widgets so
this is this to be nice you as I'll see
how this works essentially we have a
class P inherits from float layout and
now we have P and what we're gonna do
here is on a few widgets and since this
inherits from float layout we can use
the size pause and or what am I saying
size pause size hint and pause hints
that we've used before so let's just
start off with a label I will just say
the label has a text and the text will
just say like you
you pressed the button hello that okay
and then we'll do size underscore hint
and for size underscore hint it can be
honestly whatever you want it does
really matter I'm just gonna do 0.6 0.2
and 4 pause underscore hints this one
will be a bit different I want this to
be at the top of the screen
so we'll do X and we'll do 0.2 just so
we get that centered and then we'll do
why I should not why let's do top of one
so we go right up to the top now I'll
copy this I'm just going to do the same
or a similar thing with a button
so we'll just change this to B button
and you guys can see how this works so
the button instead of going for 0.6
let's go 0.8
let's go X 0.1 and we'll change this to
Y and 0.1 so now if we actually use P it
should have like a label up top and then
a button slightly below it and that's
all we need and obviously you guys know
how to add things into like your classes
and float layouts and whatnot okay so we
have our float layout here we have
widgets we'll do something that in a
second but let's get into pop-up down so
essentially the content for our pop-up
is going to be P right so what we need
to do is I'm just going to say show is
equal to and we'll create a new instance
of P and that's just so that we can use
this in what we're gonna do in a second
so what I'm gonna do now is I'm going to
say pop should we say let's just say
pop-up window I don't want to name it
the same thing as the class that's why
I'm okay so pop-up window equals pop-up
and then in here we have a few things we
can use we can use first of all title
now obviously the title is gonna be
what's at the top of your box in this
case I'm just gonna say pop-up window
okay we have content now the content
remember is gonna be equal to P because
that's what we set here so say content
is or not P it's show because that's
where we're storing P and then what else
do we have well we have a we can there's
a bunch of other parameters that we can
use as well but we're gonna use a size
hint and pause hint as well so I believe
actually it might just be size I gotta
check no its size is size handicapped so
size hint and the here I'm just gonna
type none none because I don't want this
to dynamically resize I want to just be
equal to these same size no matter what
so size hint equals sorry none none and
then we're gonna do
sighs for a static size is going to be
equal to 400 400 now you can change the
position as well but by default it's
gonna come in the middle of the screen
which is probably what you want so if
you want to read the dog since you don't
do that feel free but essentially this
is what you usually will want to do now
to actually show this window you don't
have to add it to a widget or anything
like that
all you have to do is literally just do
pop-up window dot show I want to say or
is it dot huh let's see open that's what
this sir I have it open on my other
screen sighs forget ok so dot open so
once you've created this pop-up window
you have the content you've set the
sizes here the reason we do this is just
so that we override it with this like
absolute size so it doesn't try to
dynamically resize and then we just
opening it up and it'll just go on top
of whatever window we already have
created which is really nice and saves
us a lot of time now we have this pop-up
window now but how do we actually
trigger this and get it to run what what
we need to do is create a widget inside
of our widgets class ideally a button
and when we press that button we're
gonna trigger this function so first of
all I'm just gonna say well we're
already here in this widgets class I'm
just gonna say define BTN okay and BTN
will do this is just simply gonna call
popup window so we'll just do this
pop-up window don't know why that's not
showing for me anyways this should work
pop-up window Oh show underscore pop-up
is what I called it my bad show
underscore pop-up
okay so now we're just going to call
this function whenever this method is
called so to call this method well first
of all we need to create something for
widgets so like we've done before we'll
just do widgets and then in here we can
just simply create a button and I'm not
gonna worry about really sizing this or
anything I'm just gonna simply make a
button it'll say text and the text will
just be equal to press me okay and then
we'll say on underscore release all
we're gonna do is gonna do route BTN and
remember root is gonna call this widget
class which just means it's gonna call
this method okay
awesome so let's run this and see if
everything's working okay so you see a
button we say press me and when we press
press me it pops up a window that says
pop-up when
you press the button and then there is
obviously another button in here that
says you press the button now if you
want to add more things to this you
could go ahead and do that you know how
to now that we've created this little
class for it now to get out in this
pop-up you just click anywhere else on
the screen you can see it disappears and
this is really nice and I don't know I
think this pop-up looks pretty clean and
you can really you can dynamically
change the size and do a lot of things
with it I think it's very useful um so
anyway so that's gonna be it for this
video if you guys enjoy please make sure
you leave a like and subscribe and I
will see you again in another one
[Music]