hey guys and welcome back from the kV
tutorial so in today's video we're gonna
be going through how to change screens
so essentially having multiple windows
and then doing some kind of transition
between them based on like an event
occurs so the exact example that I'm
gonna be using is we're gonna have a
login form and if you type in the
password correctly it'll move you to the
next page
if not then obviously it won't move you
there so this is actually quite a few
steps so make sure you guys follow along
closely and as always all the code will
be up on tech with Tim net ok so what
we're actually gonna start by doing is
something different that we haven't done
yet so notice that I change the name of
my main app I've just deleted
essentially everything there's nothing
in my KB file to my main app instead of
just my app so now this Cavey file won't
actually load incorrectly if we remember
the naming conventions from before so
what I want to do is only use something
called a builder which will allow us to
load in the KB file no matter what the
name of it is so let's just start by
importing it so I leave us from K V dot
Lang we're gonna import builder and then
what we're gonna do is just type right
above our class we'll say K V equals
builder if I could type load underscore
file believe that's the name and then
what we'll do is put the name of our
file so my dot K V and what we're gonna
do now is we're just gonna return K V
from this my main app so essentially
what this is gonna do is this she's
gonna load up this file it doesn't
matter what the name of this file is now
and we're gonna return this file when
we're building the app so like let's
just do an example here if I say button
and I say text and we'll just go like
Tim and to see if this works just to
test and there we go we see we get a
button Tim and again because we're
loading up this KB fall it's the way
this builder thing works just you don't
have to name your K V file like the same
thing as the class ok so that's it for
Builder so what we're gonna do now is
since we're setting up screens we
actually have to use something from
Kibby which is well screens and screen
managers what we're gonna do is going to
say from Kivi dot UI x dot screen
manager import screen manager and import
screen so we're gonna set up three
classes
and they're not gonna have anything
inside of them but they're just gonna
dictate our different screens and then
our screen manager so our first class
will be our first window so I'm just
gonna say this main window okay and this
is just gonna inherit from screen and
then all we have to do in here is just
pass now I'll actually copy this and
paste this and instead of having main
window we'll do second window and then
we'll paste this one more time and
against the main window we're gonna do
what is it window manager the names of
these don't really matter as long as you
remember what they are and that instead
of screen we're gonna do screen manager
okay screen manager so essentially what
this is gonna do now is this is gonna
represent our main window which is our
login form this will represent the page
we go to next and this window manager
will just represent like the transitions
and stuff between the windows okay so
what we're gonna do now is what we will
I think we may be done actually for the
Python file so let's move over to the kV
file and start setting some stuff up so
the first thing we need to do is we're
just gonna grab this window manager and
we're gonna set what type of screens are
what screens are going to be inside of
this so the two screens we have our main
window okay and then we also have a
second window right so we'll put those
in here like that and just leave these
as you need a colon here and we're not
gonna type anything else but you just
need the colon because there is possible
options you could put so this right now
is just saying we're gonna have two
windows main window in second window if
you wanted to add a third window you do
something like third window here if I
could type this and yeah then that's how
you do that
but you'd also have to make sure that
you have a third window class here and I
think you guys probably get the point so
what I'm gonna do now is I'm just gonna
start creating the kind of forms for our
different windows now this is really
similar to what we've done before except
we just need to add a few other things
to it so essentially what we're gonna do
is gonna go May in the window like this
and then in here what we'll put is uh
first need to give it a name now the
name is gonna be how we what do you call
it call it in terms of moving between
screens so the name of this one we'll
just call this main now we'll even just
we'll just
the second window right now so we don't
forget so second window and it's for the
name here we'll just do second okay now
again these names can be whatever you
want just make sure you remember them
because we are gonna have to use them so
name main names second now all I'm gonna
do in the second window notice - it's
already here is just create a button and
on my button all I'm gonna do is just
have some text and that Texas is gonna
say go back right because if we make it
to this screen then we just want to be
able to navigate back to the other
screen so that's what we need for second
window now for main window I want to set
up this login form that essentially all
it does is is just gonna have like a
label a text input box and then a button
so we're gonna do this similar to what
we've done before with multiple grid
layouts so in case you forget we're
gonna do a grid layout and then for the
first grid layout we're gonna have calls
is one okay and then what should we put
inside here we need to put another grid
layout so the other grid layout will be
calls too
and then inside here we're gonna have a
label and Wow okay I don't know what I
just clicked to do that that was
interesting and we'll say text and for
this we'll just say is password okay
colon and then we'll put a text input
box and we're gonna need to give this an
ID so the ID for this I'll just say is
passed W okay and then in here what
we'll do is we'll say for text input
multi-line equals false okay so that's
all we need for here now we actually
know we need to add a button sorry give
me on that one so add a button and this
button is just gonna have a text that
says submit and we're gonna have an on
press event which were actually on
release event which we'll do in just a
second and we're gonna have a non
release event here so let's just do that
so we don't forget let's do a quick
summary of what we've done so
essentially this is all like this is
probably a review except for this part
here of what we've done before so we
just created a very basic form all we're
going to do is we have what do you call
it the text input which is going to just
ask you for a password you can type and
password and then we're just gonna check
here if the password is a certain value
and if it is then we're going to
transition to the other window so the
way that we transition to the other
windows is we
you this we do app JA root dot current
okay and then we set it equal to the
window we want to go to so in this case
if we hit submit we want to go to the
second window that that is this right
now the name of that window is second
like we named it here so that's all
we're gonna do we're gonna say app dot
root current equals second now we can
actually copy this and we can paste it
right here as well and here though if we
want to go back we won't want to do the
name main so that's what we'll do and
actually let's just tab this in here
underneath on release and this should be
working fine so let's run this quickly
and assuming I didn't make any mistakes
which I probably did we should be
working invalid property property name
multi-line I can't do equals false I
have to do : false believe that's the
issue yes there we go okay so we have a
little login window make it a bit
smaller you can see it resizes so I'd
type something in here hit submit and
you can see it brings me over to my
other page and then if I hit go back it
brings me back now notice though that
these transitions are probably not ideal
moving like left right or just keep
moving to the left but we want to go
left and then to the right so how do we
do that well luckily there is a way that
we can do that so on the release here
what we're actually gonna type in type
root dot manager dot transition assuming
I spell this correctly so root dot
manager dot transition dot direction and
then this is gonna be equal to what
direction I wanted ghost in this case
we're gonna go left okay and then if we
copy this and we paste it here we can go
right so now let's check this out and
see if I did this correctly okay so if I
hit submit you can see removing to the
left now watch this if I hit go back we
move to the right so you can see that
it's kind of going back and forth and
that's awesome okay so the last thing I
want to do for this video is I want to
make it so it only lets us go to the
next page if we type this password
correctly right so how can we do that
well we just need to do a little bit of
logic inside of here
so the reason we gave this an idea so
that we can check the value so on on
release here let's go in here and let's
do a bit of logic
let's just say if or we'll say second if
and I will say Pass W dot txt equals
equals and let's just make the password
Tim in this case we'll say else we're
just gonna stay on this main page so
we'll go to second if the password is
Tim otherwise we'll go we'll just stay
on the main page okay so let's try this
if I hit submit I'm not typing a
password it's not working if I type T I
doesn't work if I type Tim you can see
we go to the next page and that is
essentially oh we should probably
actually would want to clear this as
well so we could do that too you know
what let's not worry about that right
now how am I do in the next video but
essentially that's how that works
this is how we can go between multiple
windows if you want to create another
window create another class inherit from
screen same thing here and then you can
kind of lay out the navigation for
yourself so if you guys enjoyed the
video please make sure you leave a like
and subscribe and I will see you again
in another one
[Music]